Igor Simões iigor.simoes@gmail isol2@cin.ufpe.br +55 81 9-9859-2804

Address

R. João F. Lisboa, 120 Bloco 7 apto 302 Várzea 50741-100 Recife, Pernambuco Brazil

WebsiteLinkedInGitHub

Igor Simões de Oliveira Lima

Software Engineer

About Me

Currently, I'm a Software Engineer at Locus Custom Software working with Python/Django and ReactJS. In early 2020 I obtained my Master degree in Software Engineering at Federal University of Pernambuco (Recife, Brazil). Bachelor in Computer Science at Federal University of Alagoas (Arapiraca, Brazil). I was a research fellow at Laboratory of Analysis, Modeling and Programming (LAMP) at Federal University of Alagoas. In 2016, I was resident in the Sequential Course of Complementary Training in Test Analysis by the Motorola Mobility at CIn-UFPE where I worked as a QA Developer integrating the Automation Team, performing the automation of testing cases in mobile applications.

Education

Jul 2017 - Jan 2020, Federal University of Pernambuco - CIn

Master's degree in Computer Science. Main area: Software Engineering and Software Testing.

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016, Federal University of Pernambuco - CIn

Sequential Course of Complementary Training in Software Engineering with emphasis on Software Testing by Motorola Mobility and CIn-UFPE.

Feb 2011 - Jan 2017, Federal University of Alagoas

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science.

Experience

Sep 2019 - Present, Software Engineer, Locus Custom Software

Currently, developing web applications with Django and ReactJS. Designing and implementing testing methodologies and helping my teammates with code review and TDD.

Knowledge adquired: Django, ReactJS, Flask, FastAPI, Docker.

Jul 2017 - Jan 2020, MSc. in Computer Science, CIn-UFPE

During the master's degree, I led two projects and worked on other projects with colleagues from University of Lisbon (ULisboa/PT) and University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign(UIUC/USA) under the supervision of my advisor Prof. Dr. Marcelo d'Amorim.

Project: Leveraging Diversity to Find Bugs in JavaScript Engines (MSc. thesis)

- We mined JavaScript files from open-source projects and apply techniques to violate the EcmaScript specifications in JS engines (Google V8, Microsoft ChakraCore, Apple JavaScriptCore and Mozilla SpiderMonkey).
- In this project, we reported 49 bugs and 35 of them was confirmed and 28 was fixed by the Microsoft, Apple and Google teams.
- Paper accepted at SQJ'2021.

Igor Simões iigor.simoes@gmail isol2@cin.ufpe.br +55 81 9-9859-2804

Address

R. João F. Lisboa, 120 Bloco 7 apto 302 Várzea 50741-100 Recife, Pernambuco Brazil

WebsiteLinkedInGitHub

Project: Practical detection of CMS plugin conflicts in large plugin sets

- We implemented a technique to identify conflicts in plugins in the WordPress framework, using textual diff and image recognition using openCV
- Paper accepted at IST'2020.

Project: Prioritizing Runtime Verification Violations

- Identifying specification violations in Java projects, reporting bugs and using machine learning algorithms to prioritize the results
- Paper accepted at ICST'2020

Project: LithiumSlicer

- A test minimization tool to help developers create small test inputs.
- I helped to design and implement the infrastructure to run the experiments with ULisboa colleagues.
- Available at LithiumSlicer

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016, *QA Test Analyst*, Project Motorola Mobility/CIn-UFPE

Working in Automation Team fixing and implementing test cases for mobile devices.

Knowledge adquired:

- Software testing for Motorola mobile phones:
 - GSM / 2G
 - UMTS / 3G
 - HPSA / 3.5G
 - LTE / 4G
- Analysis and Reporting in JIRA tools
- Execution of test cases:
 - Manual
 - Semi-automatic
 - Automatic
- Types of tests:
 - Black-box testing / Functional
 - Sanity
 - Regression
- Automation with UIAutomator and internal softwares

Jan 2013 - Dec 2015, *Software Developer*, Laboratory of Analysis, Modeling and Programming (LAMP) - UFAL

Developing applications for Academic Researches using Java and JavaFX. One of them was a desktop application to support the learning of physics on a digital board using JBox2D to create a environment with gravity, velocity and others metrics. I worked also in another project implementing a plugin for monitoring students actions in Geany IDE(Integrated Development Environment) to display the metrics collected in a Diango server.

Igor Simões iigor.simoes@gmail isol2@cin.ufpe.br +55 81 9-9859-2804

Address

R. João F. Lisboa, 120 Bloco 7 apto 302 Várzea 50741-100 Recife, Pernambuco Brazil

WebsiteLinkedInGitHub

Skills

Programming

- Python
 - Django
 - Flask
- Javascript
 - NodeJS
 - ReactJS
 - React-Native
 - MeteorJS

Knowledge and Tools

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

- Docker
- Linux
- Selenium

- TDD Jenkins
- PytestScrum
- JIRAKanban

Java

• ... and more

Learning

- NextJS
- Elixir
- Flutter

FastAPI

Interests

Professional

Programming, Software Engineering, Web and Mobile Apps

Personal

Music, Poems, Books, Games and working hard for Cooking.

Extras

Personal Projects

- Cerebro-yts-movies (700+ downloads)
 - A plugin for Cerebro app to search and download Movies from YTS website.